[Music]
so hello and welcome to what's new in
entering and approving time sheets my
name is Ian ktic and I'm a product
manager in business Central team uh
today I will take you through a very
short agenda of the improvements that
we've made in time sheets area is
basically evolves around how to get more
and how to be more productive while
entering a time sheet whether you're a
technician or a team member and how uh
business Central is actually helping uh
managers be more productive in approving
time sheets so the first section of uh
of this presentation is about getting
productive while entering time sheets so
the first thing that you want to do when
you work with the time sheets you want
to spend as less time as possible trying
to figure out what is the current time
sheet that I want to do so the
self-service part which is part of
almost all of our Ro centers now has a
new tile it also has a new action that
takes you directly to a current time
sheet that is based on the work date
that is set in the product what you can
see there's a new tile uh with the name
new time sheets which contains all the
time sheets where you don't have any
lines enter that you haven't started
working on yet to avoid errors and
easily spot uh missing values we've
actually made uh submit and reopen uh
actions context aware so that you don't
get in in the situations where the
errors are thrown where they shouldn't
be the status column on the time sheet
lines right now has a conditional
formatting it's going to be red and
italic if there is some required data
that is missing to be entered before the
time sheet can be
submitted to save you further effort and
time while entering time sheets what you
will see is there's a set of columns in
the time sheet lines like project
project task cause of absence chargeable
and so on these are all the columns that
are still and were available as part of
the activity details but there's a small
caveat to them these columns are now
basically dependent on your company's
setup so in case you haven't set up
causes of absence or you're not working
with projects these columns are not
going to be shown thus removing the
Clutter from the time sheet line uh
showing columns based on on the setup
has following benefits it it makes the
time sheet much easier to read much
easier to understand and it actually
reduces uh reduces time while entering
time sheets because you can you can use
keyboard shortcuts to easily copy values
from the previous
lines to make time sheet uh entry even
more efficient
we've also added extended uh
capabilities of copying time sheet lines
from your previous uh time sheets it's
not only the last one that you've
entered but we've now provided you with
an options to choose from uh either open
or submit a time sheets and to pick the
lines that you want to uh that you want
to copy to your current uh time sheet
another thing to note is in all of the
places where you will see uh time sheet
lines we have added a time sheet line
details fact box which actually allows
you to go and peek into the data and the
comments uh that are related to a
details of either resource or the
project or the tasks that you have been
uh adding to the time sheet lines
there's one tip in here so for example
if you pick the first line in the in the
time sheet in the time sheet lines page
uh the business Central will ask you
whether you want to copy the full time
sheet or you just want to pick you just
want to copy the selected one the
default being only the selected one and
now let's switch to the demo so in this
demo I will play a role of a Terry who
might be a technician a project team
member uh filling in one of his chores
filling in the time sheets so what I
want to show you today is how we
actually help Terry enter the time
sheets as I mentioned before uh with a
new time sheet experience Terry actually
gets this new tile that takes him
directly to his current time
sheet he are the two here is the new
tile that actually lists all the all the
time sheets that don't have lines that
have been prepared by his manager and
here are the time sheets that he has in
progress so let's take him to the
current time sheet what you can see in
here are the reopen and submit buttons
now being disabled because there are no
lines that Terry has entered the status
field of the lines is uh also uh
conditionally formatted indicating that
there is something that needs to be
entered in order for Terry to proceed
what Terry will do in here is we will
just uh we will just go and utilize one
of these cool new features of copying
the time sheets from the previous one
and in here you can see that he can pick
whether he wants to see all of his pre
all of his time sheets only open ones
are the ones that have already been
submitted so he will go and copy these
two time sheets and what you can do in
here is uh for example if if if he wants
to add an extra line This is
now uh much easier because he can use f8
keyboard shortcut to Simply copy the the
the details from the previous line uh
and enter them another cool thing to
note in here is if there is some
comment since he has copied the lines
together with with comments these things
are also going to be shown in the time
sheet details U fact box and you can
also see that uh there are some
additional information about the
selected project and selected task uh
that exists in here and now that uh all
of the details have been entered you can
actually see that a submit button has
now been enabled in this way sort of
avoiding an error to happen unless there
are all the details that are needed for
the time sheet to be submitted and thus
lowering the time that is needed for the
time sheet to be
entered and to summarize the demo what
you saw in here are the new tiles that
were introduced to uh enable easier
entry of the time sheet and focus on
them uh you also saw how uh easy it was
uh for for Terry to uh copy the time
sheets uh from previous ones and you
also s saw these context senses
submit and reopen uh buttons that help
Terry uh submit time sheets without
encountering any uh errors the next
section of the uh of this session is
about more focused on the manager and on
approving uh time
sheets so one of the things that we've
noticed while looking at our Telemetry
is there's a lot of a lot of Errors
where uh that get produced by the empty
lines in in the time sheets and for that
purpose what we've decided to introduce
was a time submission policy in some
cases it is perfectly okay to have uh to
have an empty line in some cases it's
not so in order to keep the backwards uh
compatibility we've introduced a an
extra setup where you can actually say U
where you can actually choose whether
the empty lines uh are uh simply skipped
and not subm
or you want to uh you want to keep the
existing Behavior where the system will
stop and warn you if there are empty
lines uh before you submit the time
sheets uh project managers now have way
way more detail in their uh manager time
sheet by jobs or by projects available
while approving uh time sheets you can
now see a resource number and the
resource name you can actually bring
through the personalization window if
you want to uh to add it to manager time
sheets by projects uh you will also see
that uh some of the projects have worked
that is executed in Saturdays and
Sundays so these columns have also been
added we've also added a total column
per line so you can actually that
summarizes all the all the work that has
been done for a specific uh projects and
on top of that we've also brought in
this uh time sheet line details that you
already saw me present in the in the
previous demo but also so uh for the
project manager we also surface the
comments that might have been in might
have been entered in the time sheet
header as well as the comments that are
uh related to uh uh time sheet lines
there's also another thing
um another Improvement that has been
done uh while approving or rejecting
time sheets uh we have actually changed
the default when you when you approve a
selected set of time sheets the the the
default uh the default setting of
approval is only for the selected time
sheets that sort of avoids we got
feedback that that that sort of insures
that less mistakes are are made and
there is less turnaround in the time
sheets when they are getting
approved and the best way to to show it
is actually to see it in action so in
this demo I'm playing the role of terce
manager and uh he as a manager when
looking at the period uh sees a set of
time sheets that up ing uh his approval
what you can see in the time sheet
window at a glance Teri manager has way
more details based on which he can
decide whether a time sheet needs to be
approved or not so for example you can
see the resource number you can see
Saturday and Sunday you can see the
status the total quantity for specific
line and he can also see the time sheet
comments that might have been related or
added on a on a on a fulltime sheet
together with uh uh specific uh time
sheet line comments and additional
details that are related to a project or
task that a specific time sheet relates
to uh another thing that you will notice
you can also open the time sheet card
from here to to go and if you want to do
sort of a one by one uh look at the time
sheets but if you do want to approve
them in bulk you can always uh you can
always uh select them uh from here and
say go and let's approve those things
and in this demo uh you've seen um the
new improvements that we brought to
manager time sheets uh for projects you
see extra uh information that managers
now have uh to help with uh approving
time sheets and we also saw some of the
extra fields that uh they can add
through personalization uh to make uh to
get even more insight and to get uh fast
in approving uh time sheets and that
sort of brings us to the end of this
session uh there are two other relevant
sessions uh if you want to learn more
and that are very related to the uh time
sheet
management uh these are the sessions on
what's new in service management and
what's new in project management both of
these modules actually use time sheets
to record a time that was executed
either servicing a product or executing
uh on a um execu in a
project and if you do want to learn more
if you want to connect with us uh have
some questions or simply want to join
the conversation and influence what and
how business Central evolves in this
area please use these links uh to do so
and with that uh I want to thank you for
your time and your
attention